Brier S. Gallihugh, M.S.

989-423-6118 | Email: gallihughou@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Lancaster, OH 43130

SUMMARY

I am an experienced social psychology doctoral candidate and researcher specializing in work regarding prejudice and discrimination. I bring +7 years of experience in data science (including experimental design) and +2 years of psychometric experience resulting in +15 studies, 8 presentations across national and regional conferences, and 2 manuscripts. I am seeking to

use my data science expertise to provide data driven insights and help advance organizational goals and objectives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Language Skills: R | SPSS | SQL | Python | Git
 R Libraries: Tidyverse (e.g., dplyr and ggplot2)
- Technical Writing: Rmarkdown | Quarto
- **Software**: GitHub
- Statistical Modeling: SEM | Meta Analysis | Regression | Correlation | T-Test | ANOVA | Mediation & Moderation
- Psychometrics: Scale Construction | Scale Development | Scale Validation | EFA | CFA
- Other: Dynamic Computational Modeling | Data Cleaning | Research Design | Data Analysis | Experimental Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Quantitative Researcher, Ohio University | Athens, OH

August 2020 - Present

- Designed, cleaned, analyzed, and created visualizations for +10 research studies using R to gain insight into human behavior and attitudes as a doctoral level student.
- Applied regression analyses, ANOVA and moderation analyses to investigate human behavior and intervention effectiveness.
- Disseminated analytical insights at regional and national science conferences in the form of 3 presentations and 3 talks at departmental colloquiums and regional psychological science conferences in addition to one registered report.
- Designed and taught a hybrid modality R training workshop consisting of 10 modules across 2 days to +15 graduate students.

Quantitative Researcher, Eastern Michigan University | Ypsilanti, MI

August 2017 – August 2021

- Designed, cleaned, analyzed, and created visualizations for 5 research studies using R to gain insight into human behavior and attitudes as a masters level student.
- Applied regression analyses, ANOVA and psychometrics to investigate human behavior, evaluate intervention effectiveness and construct and investigate the validity and reliability of a new psychological measure.
- Disseminated analytical insights at regional and national science conferences in the form of 2 presentations.

SELECTED PROJECTS

Black Lives Matter Support (BLM)

August 2020 - Present

Designed, implemented and analyzed behavioral data across 5 studies investigating predictors of support for the BLM movement. Regression analysis suggested high multiculturalism and low assimilation beliefs positively predict support. A link to the source code repository can be found <u>HERE</u>

R Workshop Website

May 2023 – July 2023

• Designed and launched a R workshop companion site using Quarto and GitHub to provide reference materials (and video recordings) for how to run inferential statistics with R. The companion website can be found HERE

Christian Privilege Scale

August 2018 - August 2021

Designed, implemented and analyzed a scale development project to create a valid measure of Christian privilege awareness
among Christian samples. Initial factor analysis and correlation analysis suggest the scale captures the intended privilege
metric. A link to the source code repository can be found HERE

PUBLICATIONS AND OTHER MEDIA

Gallihugh, B. & Rios, K. (2023). Inter-ethnic ideologies as predictors of black lives and all lives matter. In Preparation

Mackey, C. D., Gallihugh, B., Rios, K., & Gervais, W. M. (2023). Faithless found: Replication and extension of Gervais (2011). The International Journal for the Psychology of Religion. Accepted In Principle (as a registered report)

Gallihugh, B. (2023). Statistical Analyses in R: A Two Day Crash Course. Hybrid Workshop at Ohio University. Materials can be found **HERE**

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Experimental Psychology

Ohio University (Athens, OH) Expected: December 2024

Master of Science (M.S.) in General Experimental Psychology

Eastern Michigan University (Ypsilanti, MI)

Saginaw Valley State University (Saginaw, MI)

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Psychology

August 2020 - Present

August 2017 - August 2021

August 2012 - May 2017